Guide to a Research Collection on Gay Sexuality and Activism MSS.500
Fales Library and Special Collections
Research Collection on Gay Sexuality and Activism
1915-1998
1964-1971
Fales Library and Special Collections
Poynton, Jerome
MSS.500
1 linear foot in one record carton
An anonymous gay man living and working in New York during the 1970s through the 1990s accumulated this material related to gay sexuality, as well as gay rights and activism. This collection contains pornographic and erotic magazines, gay activism support and informational material, and news clippings.
Arrangement
The magazines, booklets, and pamphlets were arranged by student workers in alphabetical order by title. The remainder of the folders were left in the order in which it was received at the time of donation. All folder titles were generated by student workers.
Biographical Note
The collection creator was a friend of the donor, Jerome Poynton, who wished to keep the creator's name anonymous. The creator wrote publicity material for various prominent New York museums, as well as free-lance writing. The creator passed away in 1994.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to researchers. Appointments are necessary for the use of manuscript and archival collections.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains an assortment of gay pornographic and erotic magazines from the 1950s to the 1970s, illustrating the sexual and recreational interests of a gay man living and working in New York during this time. Pamphlets, informational booklets, and news clippings share information on social and cultural analysis, as well as topics of concern for the gay community including homosexuals in the Armed Forces, law reform, homoeroticism, the homophile movement, psychology, gay activism, crime, religion, and AIDS. This collection represents the concerns and interests of a gay man during the 1950s to the 1990s, as he expressed his sexuality and kept current on social and political issues impacting the gay community.
Custodial History
This collection was accumulated by an individual who gifted the material to Jerome Poynton in 1994. Poynton donated the material to the Fales Library, between 2016-2017.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was donated by Jerome Poynton, between 2016-2017; the accession number associated with this gift is 2017.090.
Gay liberation movement -- United States.; Homophobia.; Clippings (information artifacts); Gay rights.; Magazines (Periodicals); Gay men -- Sexual behavior.; Gay erotica.; Poynton, Jerome
- The Armed Services and Homosexuality, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- The Babco Men, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Ball Magazine, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Beau, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Body Beautiful: Studies in Masculine Art, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Boldfinger, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Champions All, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- The Challenge and Progress of Homosexual Law Reform, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- drum: sex in perspective, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Face and Physique, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- FORMosus, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- The Fountain: Voice of the Gay Northwest, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Gay Freedom 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Gay Studs, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- The Griffin: News of Gay Liberation, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Gunnison Jr., Foster. An Introduction to the Homophile Movement, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Hamilton, G. V. and G. Legman. On the Cause of Homosexuality: Two Essays, the Second in Reply to the First, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Harding, Carl B. Education Handbook: Individual and Group Projects and Organizational Techniques, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- The Homosexual in our Society: Transcript of a KPFA-FM Berkeley radio program, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Husky, undated (Box 1, Folder 20)
- J. Brian Presents Bob Anthony's BeefCake!, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- L.A. Hot, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Magpie of California, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Male Nudist Portfolio, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Male Pose, undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Man Handle, undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Mandate: The International Magazine of Entertainment and Eros, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- MANual, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 28)
- mars, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Marshall, George. The Beginner's Guide to Cruising, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Mr. Sun, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- National Probation and Parole Association Journal, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Orpheus: Alternative University, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- The Paper, undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Playguy: The Magazine of Male Erotica, undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Scimitar, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Sherman, S. P. Porro Unum Est Necessarium or The Gaiety of Socrates, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Silverstein, Charles. Journal of Homosexuality, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Social Progress: A Journal of Church and Society, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Sexology: The Authoritative Guide to Sex Education, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Sexual Behavior: How Shall We Define and Motivate What is Acceptable?, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 41)
- Sutton, Richard L. Gay Marriage Guide, Vol. 1: Complete Homosexual Photos, circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- Together, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- Tomorrow's Man, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 44)
- Treese, Robert L. Homosexuality: A Contemporary View of the Biblical Perspective, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 45)
- Wild One, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 46)
- Young Chops, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 47)
- ZEBRA'z: Distinguished Merchandise for the Alternative Lifestyle, 1997-1998 (Box 1, Folder 48)
- Cultural and Social Analysis in the News, 1953-1970 (Box 1, Folder 49)
- Mail from the 1970s, 1970-1979 (Box 1, Folder 50)
- Opera Memorabilia and Reviews + Articles about Judicial Issues of the Time, 1975-1976 (Box 1, Folder 51)
- Materials Concerning Gay Community, 1976-1978 (Box 1, Folder 52)
- News Clippings re: activism, theater, crime, social issues, AIDS, religion, travel, film, and politics, 1957-1990 (Box 1, Folder 53-56)